你看起来就像超人
You look like a superman.
我很紧张
I'm nervous.
你会赢的
You're gonna kick ass.
我觉得你妈妈
I think your mom's
想引起你的注意
trying to get your attention.
看看这个
Check it out.
你可不聋
You're not deaf.
我为你骄傲
I'm proud of you.
还不是一样
Close enough.
145磅! Johnson! Miller!
145 pounds! Johnson! Miller!
我要上场了
Gotta go.
祝你好运
Good luck.
House
House.
我知道你没睡着
I know you're not asleep.
如果你不是我那疲劳的大脑的产物
That insight would beabca lot more impressive
这种洞察力会让人更为印象深刻
if you weren't just aabcproduct of my exhausted brain.
你怎么不好奇我为什么在这儿?
Aren't you curious about why I'm here?
我好奇你为什么不穿法国女仆装
Curious why no french maid's outfit.
不穿紧身裤
No spanky pants.
我是一种幻觉...不是性幻想
I'm a hallucination... not a fantasy.
这是失眠abc四天没有眼球速动期睡眠会导致...
It's insomnia.Four nightsabcwithout rem sleep can cause--
也许这能解释为什么你产生幻觉
That might explain whyabcyou're hallucinating.
但不能解释为什么你会看到abcWilson死去的女朋友
Doesn't explain why you'reabchallucinating wilson's dead girlfriend.
也许是我那不为人知的内心abc想勾引Wilson到我的卧室来
Probably just my secret and very unconsciousabcdesire to get wilson into my bedroom.
或者是对Kutner之死的罪恶感abc让你想起了对我的死有多内疚
Or maybe your guilt of kutner's suicideabcreminds you how guilty you felt about me.
谁在乎你为什么在这?
Who cares why you're here?
好好的睡一晚 你就会消失了
A decent night's sleep, you won't be.
看来我要多呆几个小时了
Guess I'll be around a few more hours.
要喝咖啡吗?
Need some coffee?
会上瘾的物质无法代替自然的恢复方式
Addictive substances are noabcsubstitute for nature's healing balm.
快点搞定 我要睡觉
Let's make this fast. I need to sleep.
14岁失聪少年听到假想的爆破声
Deaf 14-year-old startedabchearing imaginary explosions.
爆炸声感综合征 真酷
Exploding head syndrome. Cool.
显然他的脑子知道怎么听声音
Well, obviously hisabcbrain knows how to hear.
病人四岁起失聪 脑膜炎的并发症
Patient went deaf at age four.abcComplication of meningitis.
为什么不进行耳蜗移植?
So why no cochlear implant?
通常会怀疑是失眠 但是他没有
Usual suspects are insomnia,abcwhich he doesn't have, migraines,
也没有偏头痛 CT上也没显示出脑部损伤
which he doesn't get, and headabctrauma which didn't show up on the ct.
该死的假想笔
Damn imaginary pen.
所有字都是妈妈签的 父亲死了?
Mom's signature's on everything. Dead Dad?
恐怕不是 父亲是精子捐献者abc医疗记录再干净不过了
No, I doubt it. He was a sperm donor.abcMedical cords couldn't be cleaner.
- 剩下的就是颞叶癫痫了abc- 错误
- So we're left with temporal lobe seizure.abc- Wrong.
在摔跤场不会没人会注意到他癫痫发作
Someone at the wrestling meetabcwould have noticed a seizure.
可能看起来仅仅像腿部受到重击
Could have just lookedabclike a bad shot to the leg.
带他去癫痫实验室abc看看他的大脑会不会再次失控
Put him in the seizure lab. See ifabchis head blows up all over again.
你打算忽略你自己的潜意识?
You're gonna ignoreabcyour own subconscious?
岂不是瘸子给瞎子引路
Gonna be the limp leading the blind.
我要一张处方 开安眠药
I need a 'scrip, for sleeping pills.
邻居的狗害得我睡不着觉abc奇怪的是还毒不死它
My neighbor's dog'sbeen keeping me awake,abcand seems strangely invulnerable to poison.
为什么快成为abc第二漂亮的Chase医生在这?
Why is the soon-to-be-second-prettiestabcdr. Chase here?
我把这当做祝贺
I'll take that as a congratulations.
我们在讨论一个病例
We're discussing a case.
他为什么要合上文件?
Why did heclose that file?
两周内就举办婚礼?
Wedding in two weeks?
我会说是你怀孕了abc但我不认为Chase已经成熟到能制造精子
I'd say you were pregnant, but I don't thinkabcchase's bodyis mature enough to produce sperm.
只是个小典礼 何必要等呢?
It's a small ceremony. Why wait?
祝你好眠
Nighty night.
没做演讲就给你药了? 他想让你出去
Drugs with no lecture? He wants you out.
有趣的病例吗?
Interesting case?
疑似前列腺癌 转到急诊室的
Possible prostateabccancer came into the E.R.
笔筒
Pencil cup.
难怪他的前列腺会扩大
No wonder his prostate's enlarged.
里面塞满了撞球杆和雪茄
It's full of pool cues and cigars.
Chase的伴郎要婚礼当天才能赶到
Chase's best man doesn't getabchere till the day of the wedding,
所以我让Wilson来办他的单身派对
so I asked wilson toabcthrow his bachelor party.
退休了的牧师都没空办?
No retiredabcministers available to plan it?
Chase不想要什么大型的乱哄哄的派对
Chase doesn't wantabcsome big,raucous party.
她的一面之词
So she says.
幸好 这个世上总有人abc准备好站在正义的一方
Luckily,there are people in this worldabcready to stand up for what's right.
不不不 我不要 我不要你来...
No, no, no, I don'tabcwant--I don't want you to--
听着 有两件事我能做好
Listen, two things I do well.
单身派对的排名接近榜首
Bachelor parties rank towards the top.
我来帮忙 明白吗?
I get to help, right?
从5赫兹开始
Starting five hertz.
整个诊断讨论中
House made it through thatabcentire differential
House居然没有嘲笑病人不去做耳蜗移植
without mocking our patient forabcnot having a cochlear implant.
病人不想进行移植是abc因为他觉得现在很好
The patient doesn't want an implantabcbecause he's comfortle with who he is.
这很令人敬佩
It's admirable.
他失聪了 这不是一种身份abc这是一种残疾
He's deaf. It's not anabcidentity,it's a disability.
这也是一种文化abc聋人有自己的学校 自己的语言
It's also a culture. The deaf haveabctheir own schools,their own language.
- 还没有形成尖峰abc- 加大到20赫兹
- Still no spiking.abc- Going to 20.
任何能用一副3块钱耳塞模拟的abc不算是文化
Anything I can simulate with a $3. 00abcpair of ear plugs is not a culture.
没有癫痫的迹象 颞叶活动正常
No sign of seizure. Temporalabclobe activity is still clean.
医生...医生 他有一只眼睛看不见了
Doctors... doctors,heabccan't see. One of his eyes.
瘸子给瞎子引路
The limp leading the bld.
这话有什么含义吗?
Is that supposed to mean something?
我不觉得
I didn't think so.
那么爆炸声感综合征加上视觉丧失
So exploding headabcsyndrome,plus vision loss.
锁骨下动脉窃血综合征
Subclavian steal syndrome.
动脉的缺损加上持续的手臂运动abc会使血液倒流进大脑
Vascular defect coupled with constant armabcmovement could siphon blood flow from the brain.
- 我们该做个血管造影 检查他的...abc- 你们尽力而为
- We should do an angio,checkabchis-- - Knock yourselves out.
我为什么知道他会失明?
How did I know he was gonna go blind?
别装可爱了 Gazoo"摩登原始人"中角色abc你在我的脑子里 你就在这儿
Don't get cute, gazoo. You're inabcmy mind. You're obviously there.
C-反应蛋白
C-reactive protein.
我注意到他的档案中abcC-反应蛋白有点轻微上升
I noticed in his file itabcwas slightly elevated.
我想癫痫实验室的压力abc会使得炎症加剧 导致视神经炎
I figured the stress of the seizure lab wouldabcdrive inflammation even higher, lead to optic neuritis.
这比"瘸子给瞎子引路"要清楚的多了
That's a lot clearer than "theabclimp leading the blind."
这只是一个小闪光点 我没办法说清
It was just a glimmer. Iabccouldn't put it into words.
这几乎不可能发生
It was a long shot.
我甚至都不记得C-反应蛋白水平了
I don't even remember theabcc-reactive protein level.
很显然你记得 只是你不知道而已
Obviously you do. Youabcjust don't know it.
乔戈里峰有多高?
How high is k2?
- 我不知道abc- 我也不知道
- I don't know.abc- Me neither.
但是几年前我读过一本关于它的书
But I read a book about it years ago.
- 凶残性感的夏尔巴人住在山上 超过...abc- 28,251英尺
- Fierce, sexy sherpa on theabccover, being over-- - 28,251 feet.
真酷
Cool.
一张访问我大脑的全天候通行证
An all-access pass to my own brain.
- 去给那孩子放点音乐abc- 为什么
- Go play the kid some music.abc- Why?
另一个几乎不可能成功的尝试
Another long shot.
我们用碘酒染色来追踪abc你脖子和手臂的血液流动
We're using iodine dye to trackabcblood flow in your neck and arm.
House 你在干什么?
House, what are you doing?
我看起来像在干嘛? 挑战恶势力
What does it look like I'mabcdoing? Fighting the power.
感觉得到吗? 很不错吧?
Feel that? How cool is that?
很显然你的母亲abc并不在乎你失去了些什么
Apparently your momabcdoesn't care what you're missing.
你是个混蛋
You're an ass.
他说他的腰部感觉到了振动abc而不是手
He says he feels the vibrationsabcin his abdomen, but not his hands.
这意味着什么?
What does that mean?
这是一种新的症状 神经病变
It's a new symptom. Neuropathy.
我以为你要去睡一会
Thought you were gonna get some sleep.
病例变有趣了
Case got interesting.
多像个动物园
Like the zoo.
除了可以在玻璃上随便敲之外
Except you can bang on theabcglass as much as you want.
你怎么会知道神经病变的?
How did you know about the neuropathy?
真是个好问题
Good question.
别打哑谜了
Enough with the riddles.
告诉我
Tell me about it.
想想"摔跤记录"
Think "wrestling record."
欺诈
Juggling.
不 双肩着地 三次双肩着地
No, pins. Three pins.
病人在过去的三场比赛中abc都被对手双肩压地
Patient was pinned inabchis last three matches.
导致了他的比分
Leading up to that,he was 15 and 0.
我猜感觉敏感度降低使得他丧失了平衡
I figured his balance wasabcoff from diminished sensation.
可能是脑瘤导致的颅内压升高
Could be increasedabcicp from a brain tumor.
在头部CT里漏看了这个?
That we missed on the head ct?
为摔跤减肥可能导致横纹肌溶解
Cutting weight for wrestlingabccould have led to rhabdomyolysis.
他三个月前刚刚提升了一个重量级
He just went up a weightabcclass three months ago.
Foreman是对的
Foreman's right.
实际上 颅内压升高可以解释问题
Actually, increased icp could make sense.
- 你刚才说...abc- 我当时在思考
- You just said--abc- I was processing.
这也使一个新症状浮现出来
It also puts a new symptom on the table.
他的失聪
His deafness.
如果是Ⅱ型神经纤维瘤abc而不是他小时候得的脑膜炎导致的呢?
What if it was caused by nf2 cancerabcinstead of his childhood meningitis?
那么说脑膜炎是一种巧合?
So meningitis was a coincidence?
或者是肿瘤抑制免疫系统后的副产品
Or a byproduct of theabccancer suppressing his immune system.
给他做头部的核磁共振
Mri his head.
如果按你说的是神经纤维瘤病Ⅱ型abc他的耳聋也许可治
If you're right about nf2,hisabcdeafness may be reversible.
我安排好 跟病人谈谈
I'll set it up and talk to the patient.
你俩... 有空不?
You two... doing anything?
你知道什么是"破碎牛仔"?
You know what a broken cowboy is?
House列的任务清单上有
It was on house's list of requirements.
我想到三种可能
I have three theories.
为什么House如此上心abc这个单身派对的事?
Why is house so into thisabcbachelor party thing?
他对单身派对着迷还需要理由?
He needs to have a reason toabcbe into a bachelor party?
他做很多事都是有理由的
He needs a reason to be into anything.
把你钱包给我
Give me your wallet.
House可能是想怂恿Chase出轨abc害他们分手
House could be trying to temptabcchase into cheating. Break them up.
你认为House喜欢Cameron?
You think house is into cameron?
我认为House喜欢Cameron喜欢他
I think house is intoabccameron being into him.
她嫁给Chase就会粉碎这个幻想
Marrying chase wouldabcshatter that fantasy.
如果Chase真出轨abc那他们本就不该结婚
If chase cheats, then they shouldn'tabcbe gettingvmarried in the first place.
这么说你觉得 House灌醉Chaseabc鼓动他犯错 没有问题?
So you're okay with house getting chaseabcsmashed enough to make a stupid mistake?
醉酒不会改变你abc只会显出你的本性
Being drunk doesn'tvchange whoabcyou are. It just reveals it.
你觉得她能做"破碎牛仔"不?
You think she can do the broken cowboy?
老天 但愿她能
God, I hope so.
神经纤维瘤病Ⅱ型是种极其慢性的癌症abc可治愈性很大
Nf2 is an extremelyvslow-grongabccancer, which makes it very treatable.
如果诊断正确 取出肿瘤后abc你也许能恢复听力
If we're right,taking out the tumor meansabcthere's a chance you'll regain your hearing.
不 他说你必须做
No. He said you have to.
怎么了?
What's wrong?
他希望你治疗癌症 但让他保持耳聋
He wants you to treat theabccancer, but leave him deaf.
呃 抱歉 不是想怎样就怎样的
Uh, sorry. Doesn't work like that.
没事的
It'll be okay
我会不得不转校
I'd have to change schools.
很可能再见不到你
I'd barely see you.
如果不治好病
You won't see me at all
你可能根本见不到我了
unless you get better
照影显示颅内压稍高abc但神经附近无异物
Imaging shows slightly elevated icp,abcbut no masses on or around the nerves.
不是癌症
It's not cancer.
第四脑室壁有轻微弯折
Slight bowing in theabcwall of the fourth ventricle.
还是有肿瘤的可能
Could still indicate a tumor.
我们拍了照
We brought pictures.
你让我做这个侦察任务--
The fact that you sentabcme on a scouting mission--
不准有女人
No skirts.
没邀请你
You're not on the guest list.
单身派对是古老又神圣的男性仪式
Bachelor parties are an ancient andabcsacred male ritef passage.
脑室弯折可能是原本存在的结构异常
The ventricle bowing is most likelyabca pre-existing anatomical anomaly,
而非肿瘤的迹象
not the indication of a tumor.
不做脑部活检就不可能确诊
No way to know forabcsure without a brain biopsy.
如果喝够多酒abc我很可能会上一个脱衣舞女
If I get drunk enough,there's a chance Iabcmight make out with one of the strippers.
或者成为一个
Or become one.
成交
Sold.
我们不能仅凭直觉就在病人脑袋上打洞
We can't just drill into ourabcpatient's brain on a hunch.
哦 老天 不要她
Oh, god, not her.
就是她害我上了麦道夫的当
She's the one that gotabcme hooked in with madoff.
Taub是对的 不是癌症
Taub's right. It's not cancer.
是 不惜一切 放弃一个诊断abc就因为它难以被证明
Yeah, by all means, abandon a great diagnosticabctheory because it's difficult to prove.
做活检 我们需要看到abc第四脑室更清晰的图像
Do a biopsy. We need to take aabcbetter look at his fourth ventricle.
或者只是早先的图像
Or an older look.
他母亲绝不可能在毫无缘由的情况下abc同意我们开脑
The mom's never gonna let us touchabchis brain without some evidence.
病人几年前鼻子骨折abc医院可能做过磁共振成像
Patient broke his nose years ago.abcHospital could have done an mri.
好吧
Okay.
我第三个妻子和我私奔abc主要是为了逃避House办的单身派对
The main reason my third wife and Iabceloped was to avoid house's bachelor party.
你看过"罗马帝国情艳史"没?
Have you seen caligula?
我病人现在的大脑图像...
My patient's brain now...
和3年前的比对 任何差异?
versus three yearsabcago. See any difference?
他在说服你不要这个派对?
Is he telling you to avoid the party?
我宣誓过不做任何伤害
I took an oath to do no harm.
好啊 那就别来
Sure, don't come.
如果你希望你的婚礼誓言变得毫无意义
If you want your weddingabcvows to be meaningless.
这话另有深意啊
This should be interesting.
你将向一个特别的女人许诺终身abc这很美好
You are going to commit to that oneabcspecial woman forever, which is beautiful.
但如果你的许诺在婚礼前后并无区别
But if your commitment the day after the weddingabcis the same as your commitment the day before,
那婚礼的意义何在
then the wedding meant nothing.
这里没有任何逻辑问题abc所以如果你希望你的婚姻有所意义
So, and I seeno logical way aroundabcthis, if you want your marriage to matter,
你必须在婚前变成一个abc肆无忌惮 尽情放纵 淤泥覆盖的混球
you have to be a wanton,trolling,abcmuck-covered pig the day before.
你个恶魔 回见
You're evil. See ya.
第四脑室壁改变了abc老图像中 它没有弯折
The wall of the ourth ventricle changed.abcIt isn't bowed in the older scan.
说明是神经纤维瘤病Ⅱ型 对吧?
Evidence of nf2, right?
你需要做个脑部活检确诊
You'd need to do aabcbrain biopsy to confirm.
嗯 我不会去那个单身派对abc每次参加你举办的派对
Uh, I'm not going to the bachelorabcparty.Every time I go to one of your parties,
我最后都会搞得狼狈不堪abc各种不同的 难以预见的情形
I end up embarrassing myself inabcsome new and unexpected way.
和鸭子那事 很难说是难以预见啊
That whole thing with theabcduck was hardly unexpected.
我不去
I'm not going.
- 好abc- 这才不好
- Okay.abc- It's not okay.
你知道我们需要什么?
Do you know who we need?
你为Wilson举办的单身派对上abc那个脱衣舞女
That stripper you got forabcwilson's bachelor party.
你可以直接在她身上喝酒
You could do body shots right off her.
干吗提这么久远的事?
Why go back to that well?
Wilson派对都9年了
In the nine years since wilson's party,
全新一代曾经被继父虐待的热辣少女abc都已长大成人
a whole new generation of hot girlsabchave been abused by their stepfathers.
她很爱猫
She loved cats.
你怎么会记得这个脱衣舞女喜欢猫?
What made you remember theabcstripper loved cats?
Chase养猫 他们会擦出火花
Chase has a cat. They'll bond.
咳 House? 你一个人在上面自娱自乐?
Ahem, house? You, uh,abcentertaining yourself up there?
为重演"贝隆夫人"排练下而已abc你发现了什么?
Just rehearsing for the revivalabcof evita. What'd you find?
脑部活检发现神经炎症abc伴随颅内压增高
The biopsy shows nerve inflammation consistentabcwith increased intracranial pressure.
是有问题 但不是癌症
Something's wrong,but it's not cancer.
他将一辈子耳聋
He's gonna go through life deaf.
他自己没意见
He's okay with that.
他不知道自己错过了什么
He has no idea what he's missing.
他妈妈是个白痴
His mom's a moron.
由于她的愚蠢abc他要赔付下半生的幸福?
He's gonna pay for her stupidityabcfor the rest of his life?
我们任由不管?
Are we okay with that?
干吗缝合? 植入人工耳蜗
Why are you closing? Let'sabcput ina cochlear implant.
手术单上没有要求
That wasn't in the paperwork.
是么? 八成有人搞错了abc我会补上的
Really? Well, someone must haveabcscrewed up. I'll go track it down.
- 我等着abc- 好主意啊
- I'll wait.abc- That's a great idea.
让这孩子开着大脑多麻醉会
Let the kid spend more time underabcanesthesia with his skull cracked open.
我等着
I'll wait.
我出了名地爱达成目的而说谎
I have been known toabclie to serve my own agenda.
耳蜗植入对我诊断不会有任何帮助
An implant does absolutely nothingabcto help me diagnose him.
拿个植入托盘过来
Let's get an implant tray in here.
试着放轻松
Just--justabctry to relax.
在康复期...
Just during the recovery phase...
你对我做了什么?
What did you do to me?
她儿子不想要植入耳蜗
Her son didn't want the implant.
如果调试期后他还是不想要abc我就取出来
If he still doesn't want it afterabchaving time to adjust, I'll take it out.
如果他还想体验盲人文化abc我也可以弄瞎他
I'll blind him too, if heabcwants to experience that culture.
现在就取出
Remove it now.
小孩刚动了脑部手术abc现在很不稳定
Kid's just had brainabcsurgery. He's not stable.
Miller女士abc我不是想为House医生开脱
Ms.Miller, I'm not trying toabcminimize Dr. House's wrongdoing.
- 但最好...abc- 她为什么坐着?
- But the best thing...abc- Why is she sitting?
她没有吼叫 威胁 踱步 只是坐着
She's not yelling,not threatening,abcnot pacing. Just sitting.
懂了吗 House医生?
Understand, dr. House?
House! 专注点
House! Focus.
我需要你保证同意这个安排
I need you to say youabcaccept the arrangement.
没问题 你没有生气
No problem. You're not mad.
我很生气
I'm mad.
不够生气
Not mad enough.
你希望儿子能听见
You wanted your son to hear.
只是没胆量说服他植入耳蜗
You just didn't have theabcguts to make him get the implant.
一旦我儿子身体稳定了abc我要求马上取出那东西
Once my son is stable, I wantabcthat thing out of his head.
为什么这样做?
Why did you do this?
因为他无知 被一个白痴养大
Because he is ignorant, andabche's being raised by an idiot.
理由不充分啊
Not good enough.
你一般都有--
You alwaysabchave--
我的病人选择保持残疾!
My patient is opting into a handicap!
这是对其他残疾人的侮辱
It's an insult to allabcthe other gimps out there.
好吧
Okay.
但我还是要让Foreman负责这个病例
But I'm still puttingabcforeman in charge of the case.
这就是安排?
That's the arrangement?
好
Okay.
你不介意让Foreman代管?
You're okay with foreman in charge?
你打给谁?
Who you calling?
噢对 你不想别人当成疯子
right, you don't want toabclook like a lunatic.
是啊 说到这个...
Yeah, about that...
你认为我们做错了?
You think we did the wrong thing?
我不确定
I'm not sure.
我甚至不确定我们为什么这么做
I'm not even sure why we did it.
但你对Cuddy的辩解很有道理啊
Well, that argument you madeabcto cuddy sounded pretty good.
对你来说 也许是
To you, maybe.
我猜现在你该戴着单片眼镜abc穿着马裤指挥大局了
I figured by now you'd be at theabcboard in your monocle and jodhpurs.
是的 你干了件蠢事
Yeah, you did something stupid.
- 快点 嘲笑别人来开脱abc- 你为什么这么做?
- Quick, better mock someone.abc- Why did you do it?
为什么我要赐予一个人听闻的权力?
Why did I give a humanabcbeing the power of hearing?
你问上帝这个同样的问题abc他会给你同样的答案
You ask god the same question,he'llabcgive you the same answer.
病人现在发热了
Patient has a fever now too.
也许只是手术并发症
Probably just a post-op complication.
- Arnold-chiari氏畸形?abc- 没有肌肉萎缩
- Arnold-chiari? - Notabcwithout muscle weakness.
假脑瘤?
Pseudotumor cerebri?
术前检查过他眼睛abc没有视神经乳头水肿
We checked his eyes beforeabcthe surgery. No papilledema.
糖果?
Candy?
我确定Wilson的那个脱衣舞女abc名字和甜味有关
I'm pretty sure wilson's stripper'sabcname was something sweet.
也许发热不仅是术后反应
Maybe his fever is moreabcthan the post-op reaction.
他女朋友几个月前生病过
His girlfriend was sick a few months ago.
- 也许她感冒实际是EB病毒引起abc- Lolli?
- Maybe her flu was reallyabcepstein-barr. - Lolli?
他们交换唾液 病毒进入他脑部abc引发脑膜炎
They swap spit,virus travels toabchis brain, leads to meningitis,
- 导致颅内压增加abc- 我同意 Taffy?
- leads to increased intracranial pressure.abc- I agree. Taffy?
我同意
I agree.
去吧 用三氮唑核苷治疗EB病毒
Go ahead, start him onabcrivavirin for epstein-barr.
保持这样做决定
Keep making decisions like that.
能保住你在掌权的幻象
It really bolsters theabcillusion that you're in charge.
为什么你不在我的办公室?
Why aren't you in my office?
因为我懂"我的"意思
Because I know what the word "my" means.
我干了件蠢事abc你却没追着我分析原因
I did something insane, and you'reabcnot all over me analyzing why.
是件好事
It was nice.
我给那个白痴植入耳蜗abc好证明他以前有多白痴 这是好事?
I gave that idiot an implant to prove toabchim what an idiot he's been. How is that nice?
你这么做 不是为了解决病例abc也不是为了救他命 你...
You didn't do it to solve the case. Youabcdidn't do it to save his life. You...
是为了使他生活更好
did it to make his life better.
这是很体贴的行为
It was a caring act.
你的方式...是不道德 不合法的 但...
Which you did in a way thatabcwas... immoral and illegal, but...
算是婴儿学步吧
baby steps.
听着不像我们
Doesn't sound like us.
你没法强迫我参加单身派对
You can't make me go toabcthe bachelor party.
我知道
I know.
你不介意?
And you're okay with that?
我能怎么样呢?
What choice do I have?
让他们取出来
Make them take it out.
他们无法再手术
They can't operate again.
你得先养好身体
First you have to get better.
我不要这东西在我身体里
I don't want this thing in me.
Seth!
拜托 天哪
Please, god.
你刚说了什么
What did you said?
"Seth"?
是我名字?
Is that my name?
S-E-T-H?
是的
Yes.
请再说一遍
Say it again, please.
Seth.
我想他尿床了
I think he just wet the bed.
小孩脱水了 但基本稳定
The kid's dehydrated,but stable.
谢天谢地 泉涌貌似暂时停止了
Thankfully,the fountain of whizabcseems to have stopped for the moment.
在EB病毒清除前不会
Not before hosing epstein-barrabcoff the table.
开吃
Now eat up.
我们得选出单身派对的冰淇淋口味
We're gonna pick out the ice creamabcflavors for the bachelor party.
可能是全身性自体免疫疾病
Could be systemic autoimmune disease.
结节病-- 这味道像是...伏特加
Sarcoido-- thisabctastes like... vodka.
如果味道像波旁酒倒奇怪了
Well, it'd be stupid ifabcit tasted like bourbon.
- 棕色那个才是abc- 这是伏特加?
- That's the brown one.abc- It is vodka?
秘方快速冷冻
Flash frozen in a secret process.
有人在地下室捣鼓出了这个
Guy figured it out in his basement.
意大利甜酒 太有才了
Lemoncello. Genius.
症状出现的太迅猛了
Symptoms came on too hard and too fast.
结节病是进行性的
Sarcoidosis is progressive.
记得在医学院里abcDonovan上的病例讨论课吗?
Remember in med school whenabcdonovan gave grand rounds?
第三节是一个大量排尿的病例
Three was that guy who was peeing liters.
血管球性肾炎?
Glomerulonephritis?
他是个摔跤手--abc也许类固醇破坏了他的肾脏
A wrestler--steroidsabccould have damaged the kidneys.
嗯 苏格兰威士忌不错
Hmm, the scotch is nice.
那他的尿液应该变成棕色
His urine would have been brown.
Donovan排除了渗透性利尿--abc不是肾脏疾病
Donovan ruled out osmoticabcdiuresis-- kidney disease.
嗜铬细胞瘤?
Pheochromocytoma?
没有高血压 去甲肾上腺素正常
No hypertension. Plasmaabcmetanephrine's normal.
视神经脊髓炎?
Dic's?
他是晚上发病的 这是个线索
It happened at night. That was the clue.
夜间 身体侧卧 血压改变
Night, recumbent bodyabcposition, changes in B.P.
是心脏问题
It's his heart.
做个12导程心电图 观察4小时
Run a 12-lead ekg,watchabchim for four hours.
Foreman同意了
Foreman concurs.
刚才怎么一回事?
What the hell just happened?
一切都在变得黯淡
Everything started to fade away.
你越发集中精神了
You're getting better at focusing.
无视一切无关紧要的事
Ignoring everything that doesn't matter.
他看来很火大
He looks pissed.
我想他会揍我们
I think he might hit us.
你眼神是不是也比我好?
Is your eyesight better than mine?
我们得谈谈单身派对的事
We need to talk about the bachelor party.
这话题不错
Excellent topic choice.
聊手术嘛太闷了abc我骗你已经是昨天的事了
Surgery's so boring, and myabclying to you is just so yesterday.
被你说服做植入 是我的错
It's my fault for lettingabcyou talk me into the implant.
这派对会让Cameron不高兴的
Cameron is not gonna beabchappy about this party.
但另一边厢 你...
But you, on the other hand...
打算和Cameron共度余生
Plan on spending theabcrest of my life with cameron.
那么说...我得取消"放屁乐队"了?
So... I need to cancel the fart band?
不...我要你绑架我
So... I need you to kidnap me.
这才是澳洲袋鼠本色
Spoken like a true aussie.
顺便问句 知道哪能找到abc"卷铺盖上路"的乐谱吗?abc澳大利亚经典民歌
By the way, if you know where I can getabcme the sheet music to waltzing matilda...
要吃冰激凌吗?
want some ice cream?
到时咱们要弄个圣代吧台
We're having a sundae bar.
不错
Sweet.
她就叫这名字
That's her name.
圣代还是吧台?
Sundae or bar?
Karamel 焦糖布丁
Karamel.
名字里有个K
With a "K."
我希望我也可以...
I wish I could get
做耳蜗植入
an implant too.
你不需要
You don't need one.
我们都不需要
No one does.
这是好事情
It's a great thing.
它会为你打开...
It's going to open up
一个全新的世界
a whole new world for you.
我不需要新的世界
I don't want a new world.
不需要任何改变
This doesn't have to change things.
我很快回来
I'll be back in a minute.
洗手间?
Bathroom?
走廊尽头 右手边第二扇门
Down the hall,two doors on your right.
谢谢
Thank you.
我说话是不是...
Do I...
听起来和她...
sound like...
一样?
her?
这个得慢慢来
It takes time.
你还没睡觉?
You still haven't slept?
这样我反应会更灵敏
And then I have a clever response.
心电图显示 窦性心律和间隔正常
Ekg, normal sinus,normal intervals.
- 他的心脏没问题abc- 他的心脏有问题
- His heart's fine.abc- His heart's not fine.
检查的时候没出问题
The heart was fine during this test.
心律不齐藏起来了
The arrhythmia's hiding.
或者我们关于心脏的判断是错的
Or we were wrong about the heart.
可能是甲状腺的问题
Could be the thyroid.
桥本氏症可以解释排尿和脑压的问题
Hashimodo's would explain theabckid's urine and brain pressure.
脚踏车测试
Treadmill.
或者心律不齐藏起来了
Or the arrhythmia is hiding.
我们要给他施加压力abc让病人做脚踏车测试
We need to stress him. Putabcthe patient on a treadmill.
病人刚做完脑部手术
The patient just had brain surgery.
压力测试会导致脑出血 并杀死他
A stress test could cause aabcbrain bleed and kill him.
你的意见很重要
I value your opinion.
但否决你的意见更重要
I value rejecting your opinion.
你不能这么做 你太久没睡了
You're not doing this.abcYou haven't been sleeping.
其实Cuddy不是真想让你主管
Cuddy doesn'tabcactually want you in charge.
她只是不想打官司abc顺便赢一座有色人种协进会奖杯
She just wants to avoid a lawsuitabcand to win an naacp award.
如果我让你拿病人的性命冒险abc恐怕两样都办不到了
And if I let you risk our patient's life testingabcan organ we already tested, we accomplish neither.
做个甲状腺功能测试
Run a thyroid panel.
没有Foreman签字abc我们怎么把他弄进压力实验室?
How do we get him into the stressabclab without foreman's sign-off?
我们可以把Foreman灭了
We could kill foreman.
她是新来的?
Is she new?
专心点 实验室模拟压力环境abc给他来点真的压力如何?
Focus. The lab simulates stress.abcWhat if it's not simulated?
可以告诉他 他女友把他甩了
We could tell him hisabcgirlfriend dumped him.
这有点难度abc她不会离开病房超过5分钟
That's a tough sell. She never leavesabcthe room for more than five minutes.
我们可以灭了她 或者...哮喘药
We could kill her. Or... asthma meds.
可以使得心跳加速
Force the heart to beat faster.
教心律不齐现形
Revealing the arrhythmia.
- 好主意abc- 是你想的
- Nice idea.abc- It was yours.
我只离开了病房几分钟
I just left the room for a few minutes.
他把植入耳蜗扯出来了
He ripped out his implant.
你对他人生的改造到此为止
So much for improving his life.
实际上 我们挽救了他的性命
Actually, I think we just saved it.
看看这个 心律不齐
Look at that. Arrhythmia.
你关于心脏的判断是对的
You were right about the heart.
当初应该听你的
Should have listened to you.
正确的说法是 "啥时都该听你的"
The correct phrasing would be,abc"I should always listen to you."
他全身都有问题 什么东西会到处跑?
He's got problems everywhere.abcWhat goes everywhere?
血液 可能是血小板增多症
Blood. Could be thrombocythemia.
过多的血小板在全身形成凝块
Excess platelets lead toabcclotting throughout the body.
血小板计数正常
Not with a normal platelet count.
那么说凝块最先不是出现在血液abc而是出现在肺部-- 肺血管栓塞
So the clotting doesn't start in the blood,abcit starts in the lungs--pulmonary embolism.
得做个肺通气灌注扫描abc看看他的肺有没问题
Should do a vq scan,seeabcif his lungs are clear.
去吧
Go.
你确定我在Wilson的派对上有这么做?
You sure I did this at wilson's party?
上次你用的是谷酒而不是茴香酒
The last time,you used grainabcalcohol instead of the sambuca.
那也行?
And it worked?
难怪那天晚上我眉毛少一截
Explains my lack of eyebrows byabcthe end of the evening.
万能天神 赐我力量 我--abc漫画"太空超人"
By the power ofabcgrey skull, I--
所以我们要彩排
This is why we're rehearsing.
你有没想过 每次病人abc病情加重时都发生了什么事?
Ever wonder what's happeningabcevery time our patient gets sicker?
- 要想也不是现在!abc- 首个症状在他摔跤时出现
- Not right now!abc- First symptom, wrestling.
接下来 是在癫痫实验室的灯光下
Then, under the lights ofabcthe seizure lab--
你有结论麻烦赶紧说 因为这感觉--
Are you going somewhere withabcthis, because this feels--
你忙你的-- 有助思考
Just keep doing whatabcyou're doing--it helps.
接下来 是处在失明的压力下
Then, under the stress of blindness...
还有术后发烧
and post-op fever.
这些症状有什么共同点?
What do all the symptoms have in common?
发热
Heat.
要是没你 这点子该直接跳进我脑袋
See, if you hadn't been here, thatabcwould have just popped into my head.
那样的话就显得我酷多了
Which actually wouldabchave been way cooler.
Foreman 那孩子有Uhthoff症abc就是说 是多发性硬化症
Foreman, kid's got uhthoffabcphenomenon. Which means it's ms.
给他上双倍的干扰素
Start him on double-dose interferon.
我们接着排练吧
Let's get our drink on.
得先在这仁兄的死因上abc加上"化学灼伤"这一条
Not before I've added "chemicalabcburns" to this guy's cause of death.
病人对干扰素有反应
Well, the patient's respondingabcto interferon.
看来我用不着干挂名部门头头了
Looks like I can retire asabcdepartment figurehead.
Robert Chase医生
Dr. Robert chase.
我们是移民局的
We're with the department ofabccitizenship and immigration.
你最近有没有申办结婚证?
Did you recently apply forabca marriage license?
是的
yes.
根据我们的纪录abc你的工作许可过期了
According to our records,yourabcwork permit is expired.
请跟我们回去一趟
If you could come with us.
我是他的未婚妻abc我跟你们回去把事情说--
Um, I'm his fiancee.I canabccome along and clear this--
抱歉 女士 我们只带走非法移民
I'm sorry, ma'am. Illegals only.
我-- 我很肯定他们搞错了
I'm--I'm sure it'sabca mistake.
等我搞清楚怎么回事abc马上给你打电话
I'll call you as soon asabcI know what's going on.
不要让House给他惹太多麻烦
Don't let house getabchim in too much trouble.
你们将度过生命中最美好的晚上
Allow me to welcome you toabcthe best night of your life.
现在 我要宣布几个基本规则
Now, aha, a few groundabcrules for the evening.
首先要注意安全
Uh, safety is job one.
我们有18天没在工作场所发生意外伤害了
We've now gone 18 days without anabcinjury in the workplace.
没错 这些姑娘都在挣钱上法学院
Uh, yes, these girls are allabcworking their way through law school.
- 不要测试他们abc- House!
- Don't test them.abc- House!
我就知道你抵不住诱惑
I knew you couldn't stay away.
这是我的房间 你不能这么做
This is my apartment. You can't do this.
恕难苟同
Clearly, reality begs to differ.
我的家具到哪儿去了?
Where's my furniture?
- 后头放着呢abc- James!
- Out back somewhere.abc- James!
Karamel?
你老婆怎么样了?
How's your wife?
我们-- 离婚了
we--we gotabcdivorced.
- 你的猫咪呢?abc- 死了
- How is your cat?abc- Dead.
一起喝一杯怎么样?
How 'bout we go have a drink?
好的
okay.
她这么做你没意见?
You're okay with this?
这可花了我50块呢
I paid 50 bucks for this.
你们俩一起很适合abc信任就是一切
You guys are great together.abcTrust is everything.
我得出去透透气 好好玩吧
I gotta get some air. Keep it real.
你应该到外头去...
You should be out there...
享受你一手操办的脱衣舞盛宴
joying the lap dances of your labors.
我宁愿呆在这里
Eh, I kind of like it in here.
我也是
Me too.
庆祝我们诊断出多发性硬化症
To us figuring out M.S.
还有失明 神经系统疾病 心律不齐等一切
And the blindness and neuropathy andabcarrhythmia and anything else we did.
我的医疗小组是干嘛的?
What exactly did my team do?
他们穿白大褂倒挺帅
Look good in their ab coats.
除了Taub
Except for taub.
有的人只适合单干...
Some people just work better alone...
可以这么说
so to speak.
- 再来一杯abc- 不! 我不行了!
- One more drink.abc- No! I can't!
我得歇一阵子
I need to take a break.
来见见Karamel
Meet karamel.
那就再来一杯吧
Maybe one more drink.
这是什么味道?
What's that taste?
是-- 草莓吗?
Is that-- isabcthat strawberry?
House 你在里头吗?
House, you in there?
用另一间厕所 在厨房里头abc外形像只洗手盘
Use the other bathroom. It's inabcthe kitchen. Looks like a sink.
Chase舔了舞女身上的润肤露什么的abc出现了过敏性休克
Chase went into anaphylactic shock fromabcthe stripper's body butter or something.
他没事吧?
Is he okay?
有住院医生身上带着肾上腺素abc他没事了
One of the residents hadabcan epipen, so he's fine.
安全起见 我们要送他去医院
We're taking him toabcthe hospital to be safe.
好的
Okay.
我知道Chase对草莓过敏 不是吗?
I knew that chase was allergicabcto strawberries, didn't I?
所以你把Karamel请到派对上
That's why you wantedabckaramel at this party.
我建议找Karamel是因为abc她在Wilson的派对上很棒
I suggested karamel 'causeabcshe was great at wilson's party.
我知道她搽什么润肤露abc也知道Chase草莓过敏
I knew about her body butterabcand about his strawberry allergy.
我想杀死Chase
I tried to kill chase.
我为什么要这么做?abc我不想要Cameron
Why would I do that?abcI don't want cameron.
但你也见不得别人幸福
You're not a big fanabcof ther people's hapness, either.
喂
Hello.
你确定? 谢了
You confirm? Thanks.
我们救回来的那个孩子...他快死了
That kid we saved... he's dying.
不是多发性硬化症 我们搞错了
It's not M.S. We were wrong.
感谢上帝你没事 出了什么事?
Thank god you're okay. What happened?
- 那一下真不错--abc- 呃 说来话长
- It was a good--abc- Uh, long story.
你们的病人肺部衰竭abc排除了多发性硬化症
Your patient's lungabcfailure rules out M.S.
我们给他上了呼吸机
We put him on a ventilator.
- 淋巴腺肿大可能是--abc- 你们当中有人是清醒的吗?
- Uh, enlarged lymphs could--abc- Are any of you sober?
折回去 你得去医院
Turn around. You needabcto go to the hospital.
我要睡觉
I need to sleep.
我就是你
I'm you.
你无法把我关在门外
You can't just shut a door.
你想杀死Chase
You tried to kill chase.
我要让你消失
Need to push you back down.
你太危险了
You're dangerous.
是医院打来的
That's the hospital.
我不听
Not answering.
喂
Hello.
我和你的小组在一起abc我得让他们清醒过来...
I'm here with your team, tryingabcto sober them up so they can...
好诊治你快死的病人
help treat your dying patient.
是Foreman快死的病人
Foreman's dying patient.
什么会引起肺部衰竭abc和病人之前的症状?
What causes lung failure plusabcyour patient's previous symptoms?
嗜酸性细胞性肺炎
Eosinophilic pneumonitis.
白细胞积聚阻塞肺部abc引起心脏问题
White blood cells accumulate,clogabcup the lungs, lead to heart problems.
符合症状
It fits.
House 你在听吗?
House, are you there?
不是嗜酸性细胞性肺炎
It's not eosinophilic pneumonitis.
- 我要洗洗睡了abc- House 别挂 我们需要你的帮助
- I gotta crash.abc- House, don't hang up. We need your help.
- 帮不上abc- 我们可以解决这个病例
- I can't.abc- We can solve this.
晚安
Good night.
其实嗜酸性细胞性肺炎说得通
Eosinophilic pneumonitis couldabcactually make sense.
不 House之所以排除这个abc因为它会影响喉部 病人会...
No, house ruled it out because itabcwould affect the larynx. Patient would be...
声音嘶哑 但失聪的孩子很少开口abc我们无法发现这点
hoarse, which we wouldn't notice inabca deaf kid who rarely speaks.
慢着 你们每人先得来颗薄荷糖
Wait. Everyone's getting breath mints.
我们想听听Seth说话
We need to hear seth speak.
但这要把管子拔掉 会有危险吗?
But that means taking out theabctube. Isn't that dangerous?
这是为他确诊最安全的办法
It's the safest way to confirmabcwhat's wrong with him.
- 当我拔出管子时 我需要他呼气abc- 好的 呼气
- I need him to breathe out as I pull on the tube.abc- Okay. Breathe out.
说"啊"
Say, "ah."
抱歉 我们搞错了
I'm sorry. We were wrong.
重新插管前 我要检查下你的喉部
I need to, uh,suction out yourabcthroat before we reintubate.
你儿子吸烟吗?
Your son smoke?
吸烟? 我想不会
Smoke? I don't think so.
你儿子牙齿上有烟渍
Tobacco stains on his teeth.
他说他为了摔跤比赛abc曾经用嚼烟叶来减肥
He says he used to chew tobaccoabcto cut weight for wrestling.
曾经?
Used to?
嚼烟叶解释不了他的症状
Chewing tobaccoabcwouldn't explain his symptoms.
但不嚼烟叶可以
But not chewing tobacco might.
Taub是对的 是结节病
Taub was right. It's sarcoidosis.
烟草释放毒素
The tobacco releases toxins.
毒素抑制了他的免疫系统
Those toxins suppressed hisabcimmune system.
一旦停止不嚼 没有新毒素补充abc导致潜伏的症状激化
Once he quit chewing, the absee of those toxinsabckicked a dormant condition into hyper-drive.
这能治吗?
Is it treatable?
皮质醇和甲氨蝶呤对此有疗效
Usually responds toabccorticosteroids and methotrexate.
我去给他上药
I'll start the meds.
我需要安眠药
I need sleeping pills.
我打给Wilson 但他不听电话
I was gonna hit up wilson, butabche's not answering his phone.
他肯定把电话落在裤子里了
He must have left it in his pants.
因为警察发现他时 他没穿裤子abc还嚷嚷着要走路回家...
Which he wasn't wearing when theabcpolice found him trying to walk home...
怪异的是 他才从自己家里出来
oddly, from his own apartment.
安眠药
Pills.
你的病人正在康复
Your patient's doing fine.
多亏你的医疗小组
Thanks to your team.
不是嗜酸性细胞性肺炎 对不?
It wasn'tabceosinophilicpneumonitis, was it?
- 是结节病abc- 好极
- Sarcoidosis.abc- Good.
House 跟我说老实话
House, please talk to me.
打Kutner自杀后abc我就没睡过一天好觉
I haven't slept through the nightabcsince kutner killed himself.
摔跤恐怕得再等等了
The wrestling might have to wait.
我要让医生替你重新植入耳蜗
I'm gonna tell yourabcdoctors to repair your implant.
你一直说
You always said
由我来决定
that was my decision.
但上次植入后 你甚至没有试着适应几天abc就把它扯出来了
And then you ripped it out ratherabcthan live with it for a few days, even.
我是你的母亲 我有权决定
I'm your mother. This is my call.
我不知道这样是否正确
I don't know if I'm making the right one.
但我要这么做
But it's mine to make.
睡得好么?
Sleep well?